

SIMONE PIO CARONIA

Mobile Engineer | Al

PROFILE

I describe myself as a very determined person who always wants to learn new things in depth. I'm currently working as a Mobile Engineer, also focusing on AI projects. Passion for technology, sports and music has always held a special place in my life. Experiences abroad have been important, enriching my cultural background and allowing me to grow significantly.

CONTACTS

+39 3278846913

Parma (PR) - Italy

spioc999.github.io

TECH STACK

- Flutter
- Dart
- Python
- Java
- Kotlin
- Git
- Swift
- Node.is
- Docker
- Firebase
- SQL

SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Team Working
- Public Speaking
- Determination
- Creativity
- Fluent in English

HOBBIES

- Playing racket sports and the trumpet
- Performing HIIT workouts
- Discovering new places
- Building LEGO sets
- Refereeing basketball games

EXPERIENCE

Alpian Technologies (remote)

Mobile Frontend Engineer | Al

NOV 2022 - PRESENT

- Developed cross-platform mobile applications for private digital banks using Flutter and contributed to the evolution of mobile architectures.
- Created Al-powered services leveraging LLMs and Python along with modular chatbot web applications using Flutter for Web, contributing to pipeline development.
- Followed Git Flow and Agile methodologies, actively participating in Scrum processes and ceremonies within a multicultural team.

NTT Data - Rome (hybrid)

Digital Engineer

SEP 2020 - NOV 2022

- Developed a cross-platform mobile application in the e-mobility field using Flutter, assisted in defining technical solution and followed release processes, handling production issues.
- Maintained different applications using Xamarin and Java/Kotlin for Android.
- Pioneered in Elis & NTT Data's project "Smart Alliance".

Jr Mobile Developer - Internship

APR - AUG 2020

- Developed some functionalities for a new e-mobility app using Flutter, studying and analysing the framework.
- Worked collaboratively in a large team environment, complying with strict deadlines and release processes.

Jr Front-end Developer - Internship

MAR - JUL 2019

- Developed a web dashboard for monitoring sports performance using React.js.
- Integrated third-party and map services, conducting a complete feasibility study for the company.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Intelligent System Engineering

OCT 2021 - FEB 2024

Campus Bio-Medico University of Rome

- Grade: 110/110 cum laude with mention of academic career.
- Main subjects: Artificial intelligence, Cyber-security, Statistics, Mathematical optimisation and Distributed systems architectures.
- Thesis: "Securing the Federated Learning: A novel framework through Zero-Knowledge Proof and Homomorphic Encryption".

Digital Engineering Program

OCT 2018 - JUL 2021

ELIS Digital University - Rome

- Three years program that focuses on the achievement of academical knowledge and work experiences with the companies included in the "ELIS consortium".
- One-month work experience in a charity shop in Dublin to improve English language skills, thanks to close contact with customers.
- Certifications: Oracle Certified Associate Java SE 8 and TOEFL iBT (88/120 B2).

Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering

OCT 2018 - JUL 2021

Politecnico of Milan

- Grade: 110/110 cum laude.
- Main subjects: Information systems, Software design, Physics, Mathematics, Statistics and Logic.
- Final project: "ExchangeBooks: Find, Contact, Get".

Exchange Experience - Sixth Form

SEP 2016 - FEB 2017

St. Cuthbert Mayne School - Torquay (UK)

- Awarded a scholarship to attend a six-month program at a foreign school.
- Received the "Best in Year" certificate in the UK Senior Mathematical Challenge 2016.

High school diploma

SEP 2013 - JUL 2018

Technical High School "L. Da Vinci" - Trapani

- Grade: 100/100 cum laude.
- Mentioned in the "National Excellences Register of Italian Republic".